<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 C:\Grobid\grobid-0.5.5\grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.5" ident="GROBID" when="2019-09-05T11:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Generate Long-term Future via Hierarchical Prediction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruben</forename><surname>Villegas</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimei</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuliang</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sungryull</forename><surname>Sohn</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xunyu</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Honglak</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Generate Long-term Future via Hierarchical Prediction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Abstract</head><p>We propose a hierarchical approach for making long-term predictions of future frames. To avoid inherent compounding errors in recursive pixellevel prediction, we propose to first estimate highlevel structure in the input frames, then predict how that structure evolves in the future, and finally by observing a single frame from the past and the predicted high-level structure, we construct the future frames without having to observe any of the pixel-level predictions. Long-term video prediction is difficult to perform by recurrently observing the predicted frames because the small errors in pixel space exponentially amplify as predictions are made deeper into the future. Our approach prevents pixel-level error propagation from happening by removing the need to observe the predicted frames. Our model is built with a combination of LSTM and analogy-based encoder-decoder convolutional neural networks, which independently predict the video structure and generate the future frames, respectively. In experiments, our model is evaluated on the Human3.6M and Penn Action datasets on the task of long-term pixel-level video prediction of humans performing actions and demonstrate significantly better results than the state-of-the-art.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Learning to predict the future has emerged as an important research problem in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Given the great progress in recognition (e.g., <ref type="bibr">(Krizhevsky et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Szegedy et al., 2015)</ref>), prediction becomes an essential module for intelligent agents to plan actions or to make decisions in real-world application scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Jayaraman &amp; Grauman, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Finn et al.,</ref> Proceedings of the 34 th International Conference on Machine Learning, Sydney, Australia, PMLR 70, 2017. Copyright 2017 by the author(s). 2016). For example, robots can quickly learn manipulation skills when predicting the consequences of physical interactions. Also, an autonomous car can brake or slow down when predicting a person walking across the driving lane. In this paper, we investigate long-term future frame prediction that provides full descriptions of the visual world.</p><p>Recent recursive approaches to pixel-wise video prediction highly depend on observing the generated frames in the past to make predictions further into the future <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Oh et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Mathieu et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Goroshin et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Srivastava et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Ranzato et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Finn et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Villegas et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Lotter et al., 2017)</ref>. In order to make reasonable long-term frame predictions in natural videos, these approaches need to be highly robust to pixel-level noise. However, the noise amplifies quickly through time until it overwhelms the signal. It is common that the first few prediction steps are of decent quality, but then the prediction degrades dramatically until all the video context is lost. Other existing works focus on predicting high-level semantics, such as motion trajectories or action labels <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Walker et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Yuen &amp; Torralba, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lee, 2015)</ref>, driven by immediate applications (e.g., video surveillance). We note that such high-level representations are the major factors for explaining the pixel variations into the future. In this work we assume that the high-dimensional video data is generated from low-dimensional high-level structures, which we hypothesize will be critical for making long-term visual predictions. Our main contribution is the hierarchical approach for video prediction that involves generative modeling of video using high-level structures. Concretely, our algorithm first estimates high-level structures of observed frames, and then predicts their future states, and finally generates future frames conditioned on predicted high-level structures.</p><p>The prediction of future structure is performed by an LSTM that observes a sequence of structures estimated by a CNN, encodes the observed dynamics, and predicts the future sequence of such structures. We note that <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Fragkiadaki et al. (2015)</ref> developed an LSTM architecture that can straightforwardly be adapted to our method. However, our main contribution is the hierarchical approach for video prediction, so we choose a simpler LSTM architecture to convey our idea. Our approach then observes a single frame from the past and predicts the entire future described by the predicted structure sequence using an analogy-making network <ref type="bibr">(Reed et al., 2015)</ref>. In particular, we propose an image generator that learns a shared embedding between image and high-level structure information which allows us convert an input image into a future image guided by the structure difference between the input image and the future image. We evaluate the proposed model on challenging real-world human action video datasets. We use 2D human poses as our high-level structures similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Reed et al. (2016a)</ref>. Thus, our LSTM network models the dynamics of human poses while our analogy-based image generator network learns a joint image-pose embedding that allows the pose difference between an observed frame and a predicted frame to be transferred to image domain for future frame generation. As a result, this pose-conditioned generation strategy prevents our network from propagating prediction errors through time, which in turn leads to very high quality future frame generation for long periods of time. Overall, the promising results of our approach suggest that it can be greatly beneficial to incorporate proper high-level structures into the generative process.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows: A review of the related work is presented in Section 2. The overview of the proposed algorithm is presented in Section 3. The network configurations and their training algorithms are described in Section 4 and Section 5, respectively. We present the experimental details and results in Section 6, and conclude the paper with discussions of future work in Section 7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related Work</head><p>Early work on future frame prediction focused on small patches containing simple predictable motions <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Sutskever et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Michalski et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">Mittelman et al., 2014)</ref> and motions in real videos <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Ranzato et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Srivastava et al., 2015)</ref>. High resolution videos contain far more complicated motion which cannot be modeled in a patchwise manner due to the well known aperture problem. The aperture problem causes blockiness in predictions as we move forward in time. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Ranzato et al. (2014)</ref> tried to solve blockiness by averaging over spatial displacements after predicting patches; however, this approach does not work for long-term predictions.</p><p>Recent approaches in video prediction have moved from predicting patches to full frame prediction. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Oh et al. (2015)</ref> proposed a network architecture for action conditioned video prediction in Atari games. <ref type="bibr">Mathieu et al. (2016)</ref> proposed an adversarial loss for video prediction and a multi-scale network architecture that results in high quality prediction for a few timesteps in natural video; however, the frame prediction quality degrades quickly. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Finn et al. (2016)</ref> proposed a network architecture to directly transform pixels from a current frame into the next frame by predicting a distribution over pixel motion from previous frames. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Xue et al. (2016)</ref> proposed a probabilistic model for predicting possible motions of a single input frame by training a motion encoder in a variational autoencoder approach. <ref type="bibr">Vondrick et al. (2016)</ref> built a model that generates realistic looking video by separating background and foreground motion. <ref type="bibr">Villegas et al. (2017)</ref> improved the convolutional encoder/decoder architecture by separating motion and content features. <ref type="bibr">Lotter et al. (2017)</ref> built an architecture inspired by the predictive coding concept in neuroscience literature that predicts realistic looking frames.</p><p>All the previously mentioned approaches attempt to perform video generation in a pixel-to-pixel process. We aim to perform the prediction of future frames in video by taking a hierarchical approach of first predicting high-level structure and then using the high-level structure to predict the future in the video from a single frame input.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, this is the first hierarchical approach to pixel-level video prediction. Our hierarchical architecture makes it possible to generate good quality longterm predictions that outperform current approaches. The main success from our algorithm comes from the novel idea of first making high-level structure predictions which allows us to observe a single image and generate the future video by visual-structure analogy. Our image generator learns a shared embedding between image and structure inputs that allows us to transform high-level image features into a future image driven by the predicted structure sequence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Overview</head><p>This paper tackles the task of long-term video prediction in a hierarchical perspective. Given the input high-level structure sequence p 1:t and frame x t , our algorithm is asked to predict the future structure sequence p t+1:t+T and subsequently generate frames x t+1:t+T . The problem with video frame prediction originates from modeling pixels directly in a sequence-to-sequence manner and attempting to generate frames in a recurrent fashion. Current state-of-the-art approaches recurrently observe the predicted frames, which causes rapidly increasing error accumulation through time. Our objective is to avoid having to observe generated future frames at all during the full video prediction procedure. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> illustrates our hierarchical approach. Our full pipeline consists of 1) performing high-level structure estimation from the input sequence, 2) predicting a sequence of future high-level structures, and 3) generating future images from the predicted structures by visual-structure analogymaking given an observed image and the predicted structures. We explore our idea by performing pixel-level video prediction of human actions while treating human pose as the high-level structure. Hourglass network <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Newell et al., 2016)</ref> is used for pose estimation on input images. Subsequently, a sequence-to-sequence LSTM-recurrent network is trained to read the outputs of hourglass network and to Figure 1. Overall hierarchical approach to pixel-level video prediction. Our algorithm first observes frames from the past and estimate the high-level structure, in this case human pose xy-coordinates, in each frame. The estimated structure is then used to predict the future structures in a sequence to sequence manner. Finally, our algorithm takes the last observed frame, its estimated structure, and the predicted structure sequence, in this case represented as heatmaps, and generates the future frames. Green denotes input to our network and red denotes output from our network.</p><p>predict the future pose sequence. Finally, we generate the future frames by analogy making using pose relationship in feature space to transform the last observed frame.</p><p>The proposed algorithm makes it possible to decompose the task of video frame prediction to sub-tasks of future highlevel structure prediction and structure-conditioned frame generation. By doing so, we remove the recursive dependency of generated frames which have caused the compound errors of pixel-level prediction in previous methods, which allows us to perform very long-term video prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Architecture</head><p>This section describes the architecture of the proposed algorithm using human pose as a high-level structure. Our full network is composed of two modules: an encoderdecoder LSTM that observes and outputs xy-coordinates, and an image generator that performs visual analogy-based on high-level structure heatmaps constructed from the xycoordinates output from LSTM.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Future Prediction of High-Level Structures</head><p>Figure 2 illustrates our pose predictor. Our network first encodes the observed structure dynamics by</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">[h t , c t ] = LSTM (p t , h t−1 , c t−1 ) ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where h t ∈ R H represents the observed dynamics up to time t, c t ∈ R H is the memory cell that retains information from the history of pose inputs, p t ∈ R 2L is the pose at time t (i.e., 2D coordinate positions of L joints). In order to make a reasonable prediction of the future pose, LSTM has to first observe a few pose inputs to identify the type of motion occurring in the pose sequence and how it is changing over time. LSTM also has to be able to remove noise present in the input pose, which can come from annotation error if using the dataset-provided pose annotation or pose estimation error if using a pose estimation algorithm. After a few pose inputs have been observed, LSTM generates the future pose byp <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Illustration of our pose predictor. LSTM observes k consecutive human pose inputs and predicts the pose for the next T timesteps. Note that the human heatmaps are used for illustration purposes, but our network observes and outputs xy-coordinates.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">t = f w h t ,<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">LSTM LSTM LSTM LSTM LSTM LSTM</formula><p>where w is a projection matrix, f is a function on the projection (i.e. tanh or identity), andp t ∈ R 2L is the predicted pose. In the subsequent predictions, our LSTM does not observe the previously generated pose. Not observing generated pose in LSTM prevents errors in the pose prediction from being propagated into the future, and it also encourages the LSTM internal representation to contain robust high-level features that allow it to generate the future sequence from only the original observation. As a result, the representation obtained in the pose input encoding phase must obtain all the necessary information for generating the correct action sequence in the decoding phase. After we have set the human pose sequence for the future frames, we proceed to generate the pixel-level visual future.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Image Generation by Visual-Structure Analogy</head><p>To synthesize the future frame given its pose structure, we make a visual-structure analogy inspired by <ref type="bibr">Reed et al. (2015)</ref> following p t : p t+n :: x t : x t+n , read as "p t is to p t+n as x t is to x t+n " as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>. Intuitively, the future frame x t+n can be generated by transferring the structure transformation from p t to p t+n to the observed frame x t . Our image generator instantiates this idea using a pose encoder f pose , an image encoder f img and an image decoder f dec . Specifically, f pose is a convolutional encoder that specializes on identifying key pose features from the  pose input that reflects high-level human structure.</p><p>1 f img is also a convolutional encoder that acts on an image input by mapping the observed appearance into a feature space where the pose feature transformations can be easily imposed to synthesize the future frame using the convolutional decoder f dec . The visual-structure analogy is then performed bŷ</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">x t+n = f dec (f pose (g (p t+n )) − f pose (g (p t )) + f img (x t )) ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>wherex t+n andp t+n are the generated image and corresponding predicted pose at time t + n, x t and p t are the input image and corresponding estimated pose at time t, and g (.) is a function that maps the output xy-coordinates from LSTM into depth-concatenated L heatmaps.</p><p>2 Intuitively, f pose infers features whose "substractive" relationship is the same subtractive relationship between x t+n and x t in the feature space computed by f img , i.e., <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>. The relationship discovered by our network allows for highly non-linear transformations between images to be inferred by a simple addition/subtraction in feature space.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">f pose (g(p t+n )) − f pose (g(p t )) ≈ f img (x t+n ) − f img (x t ). The network dia- gram is illustrated in in</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Training</head><p>In this section, we first summarize the multi-step video prediction algorithm using our networks and then describe 1 Each input pose to our image generator is converted to concatenated heatmaps of each landmark before computing features. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We independently construct the heatmap with a Gaussian function around the xy-coordinates of each landmark.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Video Prediction Procedure</head><p>input:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">x 1:k output:x k+1:k+T for t=1 to k do p t ← Hourglass(x t ) [h t , c t ] ← LSTM(p t , h t−1 , c t−1 ) end for for t=k + 1 to k + T do [h t , c t ] ← LSTM(h t−1 , c t−1 ) p t ← f w h t x t ← f dec (f pose (g (p t )) − f pose (g (p k )) + f img (x k )) end for</formula><p>the training strategies of the high-level structure LSTM and of the visual-structure analogy network. We train our highlevel structure LSTM independent from the visual-structure analogy network, but both are combined during test time to perform video prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Multi-Step Prediction</head><p>Our algorithm multi-step video prediction procedure is described in Algorithm 1. Given input video frames, we use the Hourglass network <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Newell et al., 2016)</ref> to estimate the human poses p 1:k . High-level structure LSTM then observes p 1:k , and proceeds to generate a pose sequencê p k+1:k+T where T is the desired number of time steps to predict. Next, our visual-structure analogy network takes x k , p k , andp k+1:k+T and proceeds to generate future frameŝ x k+1:k+T one by one. Note that the future frame prediction is performed by observing pixel information from only x k , that is, we never observe any of the predicted frames.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">High-Level Structure LSTM Training</head><p>We employ a sequence-to-sequence approach to predict the future structures (i.e. future human pose). Our LSTM is unrolled for k timesteps to allow it to observe k pose inputs before making any prediction. Then we minimize the prediction loss defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">L pose = 1 T L T t=1 L l=1 1 {m l k+t =1} p l k+t − p l k+t 2 2 ,<label>(4)</label></formula><p>wherep l k+t and p l k+t are the predicted and ground-truth pose l-th landmark, respectively, 1 {.} is the indicator function, and m l k+t tells us whether a landmark is visible or not (i.e. not present in the ground-truth). Intuitively, the indicator function allows our LSTM to make a guess of the non-visible landmarks even when not present at training. Even in the absence of a few landmarks during training, LSTM is able to internally understand the human structure and observed motion. Our training strategy allows LSTM to make a reasonable guess of the landmarks not present in the training data by using the landmarks available as context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.">Visual-Structure Analogy Training</head><p>Training our network to transform an input image into a target image that is too close in image space can lead to suboptimal parameters being learned due to the simplicity of such task that requires only changing a few pixels. Because of this, we train our network to perform random jumps in time within a video clip. Specifically, we let our network observe a frame x t and its corresponding human pose p t , and force it to generate frame x t+n given pose p t+n , where n is defined randomly for every iteration at training time. Training to jump to random frames in time gives our network a clear signal the task at hand due to the large pixel difference between frames far apart in time.</p><p>To train our network, we use the compound loss from <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Dosovitskiy &amp; Brox (2016)</ref>. Our network is optimized to minimize the objective given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">L = L img + L feat + L Gen ,<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where L img is the loss in image space defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">L img = x t+n −x t+n 2 2 ,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where x t+n andx t+n are the target and predicted frames, respectively. The image loss intuitively guides our network towards a rough blurry pixel-leven frame prediction that reflects most details of the target image. L feat is the loss in feature space define by</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">L feat = C 1 (x t+n ) − C 1 (x t+n ) 2 2 + C 2 (x t+n ) − C 2 (x t+n ) 2 2 ,<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where C 1 (.) extracts features representing mostly image appearance, and C 2 (.) extracts features representing mostly image structure. Combining appearance sensitive features with structure sensitive features gives our network a learning signal that allows it to make frame predictions with accurate appearance while also enforcing correct structure. L Gen is the term in adversarial loss that allows our model to generate realistic looking images and is defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">L Gen = − log D ([p t+n ,x t+n ]) ,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where x t+n is the target image, p t+n is the human pose corresponding to the target image, and D (.) is the discriminator network in adversarial loss. This sub-loss allows our network to generate images that reflect a similar level of detail as the images observed in the training data.</p><p>During the optimization of D, we use the mismatch term proposed by <ref type="bibr">Reed et al. (2016b)</ref>, which allows the discriminator D to become sensitive to mismatch between the generation and the condition. The discriminator loss is defined by</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">L Disc = − log D ([p t+n , x t+n ]) − 0.5 log (1 − D ([p t+n ,x t+n ])) − 0.5 log (1 − D ([p t+n , x t ])) ,<label>(9)</label></formula><p>while optimizing our generator with respect to the adversarial loss, the mismatch-aware term sends a stronger signal to our generator resulting in higher quality image generation, and network optimization. Essentially, having a discriminator that knows the correct structure-image relationship, reduces the parameter search space of our generator while optimizing to fool the discriminator into believing the generated image is real. The latter in combination with the rest of loss terms allows our network to produce high quality image generation given the structure condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Experiments</head><p>In this section, we present experiments on pixel-level video prediction of human actions on the Penn Action (Weiyu <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Zhang &amp; Derpanis, 2013)</ref> and Human 3.6M datasets <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Ionescu et al., 2014)</ref>. Pose landmarks and video frames are normalized to be between -1 and 1, and frames are cropped based on temporal tubes to remove as much background as possible while making sure the human of interest is in all frames. For the feature similarity loss term <ref type="formula" target="#formula_9">(Equation 7</ref>), we use we use the last convolutional layer in AlexNet <ref type="bibr">(Krizhevsky et al., 2012)</ref> as C 1 , and the last layer of the Hourglass Network in <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Newell et al. (2016)</ref> as C 2 . We augmented the available video data by performing horizontal flips randomly at training time for Penn Action. Motion-based pixel-level quantitative evaluation using Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio (PSNR), analysis, and control experiments can be found in the supplementary material. For video illustration of our method, please refer to the project website: https://sites.google.com/ a/umich.edu/rubenevillegas/hierch_vid.</p><p>We compare our method against two baselines based on convolutional LSTM and optical flow. A convolutional LSTM baseline <ref type="bibr">(Shi et al., 2015)</ref> was trained with adversarial loss <ref type="bibr">(Mathieu et al., 2016)</ref> and the feature similarity loss <ref type="formula" target="#formula_9">(Equation 7</ref>). An optical flow based baseline used the last observed optical flow <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Farneback, 2003)</ref> to move the pixels of the last observed frame into the future.</p><p>We follow a human psycho-physical quantitative evaluation metric similar to <ref type="bibr">Vondrick et al. (2016)</ref>. Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT) workers are given a two-alternative choice to indicate which of two videos looks more realistic. Specifically, the workers are shown a pair of videos (generated by two different methods) consisting of the same input frames indicated by a green box and predicted frames indicated by a red box, in addition to the action label of the video. The workers are instructed to make their decision based on the frames in the red box. Additionally, we train a Twostream action recognition network <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Simonyan &amp; Zisserman, 2014)</ref> on the Penn Action dataset and test on the generated videos to evaluate if our network is able to generate videos predicting the activities observed in the original dataset. We do not perform action classification experiments on the  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Penn Action Video Generation Preference: We show videos from two methods to Amazon Mechanical Turk workers and ask them to indicate which is more realistic. The table shows the percentage of times workers preferred our model against baselines. A majority of the time workers prefer predictions from our model. We merged baseball pitch and baseball swing into baseball, and tennis forehand and tennis serve into tennis.</p><p>Human3.6M dataset due to high uncertainty in the human movements and high motion similarity amongst actions.</p><p>Architectures. The sequence prediction LSTM is made of a single layer encoder-decoder LSTM with tied parameters, 1024 hidden units, and tanh output activation. Note that the decoder LSTM does not observe any inputs other than the hidden units from the encoder LSTM as initial hidden units. The image and pose encoders are built with the same architecture as VGG16 <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Simonyan &amp; Zisserman, 2015)</ref> up to the pooling layer, except that the pose encoder takes in the pose heat-maps as an image made of L channels, and the image encoder takes a regular 3-channel image. The decoder is the mirrored architecture of the image encoder where we perform unpooling followed by deconvolution, and a final tanh activation. The convolutional LSTM baseline is built with the same architecture as the image encoder and decoder, but there is a convolutional LSTM layer with the same kernel size and number of channels as the last layer in the image encoder connecting them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Penn Action Dataset</head><p>Experimental setting. The Penn Action dataset is composed of 2326 video sequences of 15 different actions and 13 human joint annotations for each sequence. To train our image generator, we use the standard train split provided in the dataset. To train our pose predictor, we sub-sample the actions in the standard train-test split due to very noisy joint ground-truth. We used videos from the actions of baseball pitch, baseball swing, clean and jerk, golf swing, jumping jacks, jump rope, tennis forehand, and tennis serve. Our pose predictor is trained to observe 10 inputs and predict 32 steps, and tested on predicting up to 64 steps (some videos' groundtruth end before 64 steps). Our image generator is trained to make single random jumps within 30 steps into the future. Our evaluations are performed on a single clip that starts at the first frame of each video.</p><p>AMT results. These experiments were performed by 66 unique workers, where a total of 1848 comparisons were made (934 against convolutional LSTM and 914 against optical flow baseline). As shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>, our method is capable of generating more realistic sequences compared to the baselines. Quantitatively, the action sequences generated by our network are perceptually higher quality than the baselines and also predict the correct action sequence. A relatively small (although still substantial) margin is observed when comparing to convolutional LSTM for the jump rope action (i.e., 66.7% for ours vs 33.3% for Convolutional LSTM). We hypothesize that convolutional LSTM is able to do a reasonable job for this action class due the highly cyclic motion nature of jumping up and down in place. The remainder of the human actions contain more complicated non-linear motion, which is much more complicated to predict. Overall, our method outperforms the baselines by a large margin (i.e. 82.4% for ours vs 17.6% for Convolutional LSTM, and 86.1% for ours vs 13.9% for Optical Flow). Side by side video comparison for all actions can be found in our project website.</p><p>Action recognition results. To see whether the generated videos contain actions that can fool a CNN trained for action recognition, we train a Two-Stream CNN on the PennAction dataset. In <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, "Temporal Stream" denotes the network that observes motion as concatenated optical flow (Farneback's optical flow) images as input, and "Spatial Stream" denotes the network that observes single image as input. "Combined" denotes the averaging of the output probability vectors from the Temporal and Spatial stream. "Real test data" denotes evaluation on the ground-truth videos (i.e. perfect prediction).</p><p>From <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, it is shown that our network is able to generate videos that are far more representative of the correct action compared to all baselines, in both Temporal and Spatial stream, regardless of using a neural network as the judge. When combining both Temporal and Spatial streams, our network achieves the best quality videos in terms of making a pixel-level prediction of the correct action.</p><p>Pixel-level evaluation and control experiments. We evaluate the frames generated by our method using PSNR  as measure, and separated the test data based on amount of motion, as suggested by <ref type="bibr">Villegas et al. (2017)</ref>. From these experiments, we conclude that pixel-level evaluation highly depends on predicting the exact future observed in the ground-truth. Highest PSNR scores are achieved when trajectories of the exact future is used to generate the future frames. Due to space constraints, we ask the reader to please refer to the supplementary material for more detailed quantitative and qualitative analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Human3.6M Dataset</head><p>Experimental settings. The Human3.6M dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Ionescu et al., 2014</ref>) is composed of 3.6 million 3D human poses (we use the provided 2D pose projections) composed of 32 joints and corresponding images taken from 11 professional actors in 17 scenarios. For training, we use subjects number 1, 5, 6, 7, and 8, and test on subjects number 9 and 11. Our pose predictor is trained to observe 10 inputs and predict 64 steps, and tested on predicting 128 steps. Our image generator is trained to make single random jumps anywhere in the training videos. We evaluate on a single clip from each test video that starts at the exact middle of the video to make sure there is motion occurring.</p><p>AMT results. We collected a total of 2203 comparisons (1086 against convolutional LSTM and 1117 against optical flow baseline) from 71 unique workers. As shown in Table 3, the videos generated by our network are perceptually higher quality and reflect a reasonable future compared to the baselines on average. Unexpectedly, our network does not perform well on videos where the action involves minimal motion, such as sitting, sitting down, eating, taking a photo, and waiting. These actions usually involve the person staying still or making very unnoticeable motion which can result in a static prediction (by convolutional LSTM and/or optical flow) making frames look far more realistic than the prediction from our network. Overall, our method outperforms the baselines by a large margin (i.e. 70.3% for ours vs 29.7% for Convolutional LSTM, and 72.3% for ours vs 27.7% for Optical Flow). <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows that our network generates far higher quality future frames compared to the convolutional LSTM baseline. Side by side video comparison for all actions can be found in our project website.</p><p>Pixel-level evaluation and control experiments. Following the same procedure as Section 6.1, we evaluated the predicted videos using PSNR and separated the test data by motion. Due to the high uncertainty and number of prediction steps in these videos, the predicted future can largely deviate from the exact future observed in the ground-truth. The highest PSNR scores are again achieved when the exact future pose is used to generate the video frames; however, there is an even larger gap compared to the results in Section 6.1. Due to space constraints, we ask the reader to please refer to the supplementary material for more detailed quantitative and qualitative analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We propose a hierarchical approach of pixel-level video prediction. Using human action videos as benchmark, we have demonstrated that our hierarchical prediction approach is able to predict up to 128 future frames, which is an order of magnitude improvement in terms of effective temporal scale of the prediction.</p><p>The success of our approach demonstrates that it can be greatly beneficial to incorporate the proper high-level structure into the generative process. At the same time, an important open research question would be how to automatically learn such structures without domain knowledge. We leave this as future work.</p><p>Another limitation of this work is that it generates a single future trajectory. For an agent to make a better estimation of what the future looks like, we would need more than one generated future. Future work will involve the generation of many futures given using a probabilistic sequence model. Finally, our model does not handle background motion. This is a highly challenging task since background comes in and out of sight. Predicting background motion will require a generative model that hallucinates the unseen background. We also leave this as future work.  <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Qualitative evaluation of our network for 55 step prediction on Penn Action (top rows), and 109 step prediction on Human3.6M (bottom rows). Our algorithm observes 10 previous input frames, estimates the human pose, predicts the pose sequence of the future, and it finally generates the future frames. Green box denotes input and red box denotes prediction. We show the last 7 input frames. Side by side video comparisons can be found in our project website.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Generating image frames by making analogies between high-level structures and image pixels. ƒ pose</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. Illustration of our image generator. Our image generator observes an input image, its corresponding human pose, and the human pose of the future image. Through analogy making, our network generates the next frame.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Which video is more realistic?" Purchases Sitting Sittingdown Smoking Waiting Walking Mean Prefers ours over Convolutional LSTM 79.0% 38.0%</figDesc><table>"Which video is more realistic?" 
Directions Discussion Eating Greeting Phoning Photo Posing 
Prefers ours over Convolutional LSTM 
67.6% 
75.9% 
74.7% 79.5% 69.7% 66.2% 69.7% 
Prefers ours over Optical Flow 
61.4% 
89.3% 
43.8% 80.3% 84.5% 52.0% 75.3% 
"54.7% 
70.4% 50.0% 86.0% 70.3% 
Prefers ours over Optical Flow 
85.7% 35.1% 
46.7% 
73.3% 84.3% 90.8% 72.3% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Human3.6M Video Generation Preference: We show videos from two methods to Amazon Mechanical Turk workers and ask them to indicate which is more realistic. The table shows the percentage of times workers preferred our model against baselines. Most of the time workers prefer predictions from our model. We merge baseball pitch and baseball swing into baseball, and tennis forehand and tennis serve into tennis.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported in part by ONR N00014-13-1-0762, NSF CAREER IIS-1453651, Gift from Bosch Research, and Sloan Research Fellowship. We thank NVIDIA for donating K40c and TITAN X GPUs.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating images with perceptual similarity metrics based on deep networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dosovitskiy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Brox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-frame motion estimation based on polynomial expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Farneback</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SCIA</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised learning for physical interaction through video prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Finn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goodfellow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Levine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recurrent network models for human dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Fragkiadaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Levine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Felsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malik</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCV</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to linearize under uncertainty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Goroshin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mathieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lecun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human3.6m: Large scale datasets and predictive methods for 3d human sensing in natural environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Papava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Olaru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sminchisescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning image representations tied to ego-motion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jayaraman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Grauman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCV</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Look-ahead before you leap: end-to-end active recognition by forecasting the effect of motion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jayaraman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Grauman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv preprint:1605.00164</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Imagenet classification with deep convolutional neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Krizhevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS. 2012</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modeling of Dynamic Environments for Visual Forecasting of American Football Plays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<pubPlace>Pittsburgh, PA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep predictive coding networks for video prediction and unsupervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Lotter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kreiman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR. 2017</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep multi-scale video prediction beyond mean square error</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mathieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Couprie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lecun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR. 2016. 1</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling deep temporal dependencies with recurrent &quot;grammar cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michalski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Memisevic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Konda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Structured recurrent temporal restricted boltzmann machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mittelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kuipers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Savarese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>ICML. 2014. 2</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stacked hourglass networks for human pose estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Newell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ECCV</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Actionconditional video prediction using deep networks in atari games</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Video (language) modeling: a baseline for generative models of natural videos</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ranzato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Szlam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bruna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mathieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv preprint:1412.6604</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep visual analogy-making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS. 2015</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning what and where to draw</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Akata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tenka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schiele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generative adversarial text-to-image synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Akata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Logeswaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schiele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML. 2016b. 5</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Convolutional lstm network: A machine learning approach for precipitation nowcasting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D.-Y</forename><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W.-K</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Woo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>NIPS. 2015. 5</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-stream convolutional networks for action recognition in videos</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Simonyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zisserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Very deep convolutional networks for large-scale image recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Simonyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zisserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised learning of video representations using lstms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mansimov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Salakhudinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The recurrent temporal restricted boltzmann machine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Going deeper with convolutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Szegedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sermanet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Anguelov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Erhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Vanhoucke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rabinovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CVPR. 2015. 1</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decomposing motion and content for natural video sequence prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Villegas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR. 2017. 1</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating videos with scene dynamics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Vondrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pirsiavash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS. 2016</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patch to the future: Unsupervised visual prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hebert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CVPR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From actemes to action: A strongly-supervised representation for detailed action understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Derpanis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCV</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visual dynamics: Probabilistic future frame synthesis via cross convolutional networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bouman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A data-driven approach for event prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yuen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ECCV</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
